ANNETTE LEE

UX / UI Designer

Contact

1-(425) 480-1276



AnnetteLee.2018@gmail.com



Shoreline, WA



https://www.eigoganbare.com



Certifications

freeCodeCamp Responsive Web Design, JavaScript Algorithms & Data Structures 2020/2021

Linkedin Learning Become a Software Developer, Graphic Designer, & Digital Marketing Specialist 2020

Future Learn
Coding and Design, Apps in the
Classroom, Indie Games, &
AR/Mixed Reality
2020

UX Design Portfolio

https://eigoganbare.github.io/portfolio/

Summary

More than 5+ years of voluntarily UX design experience in user interface design system of 200+ viewers accessing my Eigo Ganbare website on a daily basis. Ability to incorporate educational classroom technology, such as designing e-learning and game-based learning platforms, as well as applying an immersive learning experience with AR apps. Singlehandedly created a team-teaching resource website used nationwide in Japanese schools. Acted as cross-cultural ambassador and a native English-speaking teacher in Japan.

UX Design - Work Experience

Web Content Creator

Eigo Ganbare Shoreline, WA 04/2010 - Present

- Create a self-initiated project of a team-teaching resource website that was designed entirely with WordPress, HTML5, JavaScript, CSS, and Adobe Creative Suite.
- Use Scrum and Agile methodologies to develop classroom materials.
- Apply design solutions with visual interactive, gaming, and augmented reality features.
- Create online web-based activities and accessibility support to facilitate student learning, utilizing H5P and user-centered gamification architecture.
 Design clickable wireframes of the teacher and classroom portal which included a built-in Nextcloud platform to enhance the user desktop and mobile experience.

UX Design & TechEdu Research Experience

Native English Teacher (NET)

Osaka Seiryo Junior High School & Senior High School Takatsuki, Japan

04/2018 - 03/2020

- Collaborated with 4-5 Japanese teachers of English to engage JHS and HS students' interest in English and foreign cultures, as well team-hosted the annual English speech contests.
- Experienced in applying iterative web based design process with KeyNote and PowerPoint and utilized other online design tools to support student engagement.
- Engaged students to think creatively and critically in teams while utilizing their iPad for brainstorming, creating mockups, and doing group research projects.
- Implemented a pen pal letter exchange program in 7 high school English classes and 2 junior high school English classes while serving as a liaison with Japanese language classes in the United States.

ANNETTE LEE

UI / UX Designer

Core Skills

- User Experience
- Prototype Design
- Usability Design
- Storyboarding
- User Interface Design
- HTML/JS/CSS
- Final Cut Pro X
- Adobe Creative Suite
- Digital Transformation
- Cross-cultural experience
- Curriculum Development
- Technological Integration

Education

Dual Bachelors of Arts in Sociology & Linguistics

University of Washington

UW Japanese Technical Program Hyogo Business & Cultural Center

Web Design Intern Sohatsu Systems Inc., Kobe

Japan Exchange Teaching Program

Assistant Language Teacher (Kasai city BOE)

Native English Teacher (C-NET)

Osaka City Board of Education Osaka, Japan

10/2015 - 03/2018

- Collaborated with 30+ JHS and ES Japanese teachers of English to assist them with the implementation of major English education and classroom technological reforms.
- Developed problem-solving, visual design interface, and deep-learning usability principles into students' worksheets.
- Integrated AR technologies, educational web app technologies, userfriendly design quizzes, and foreign cultures.
- Devised a responsive mockup strategy to increase ES students' English communication skills.
- Implemented a pen pal letter exchange program with in 12 junior high school English classes.
- Developed a portfolio to optimize the Pen Pal Project to increase international outreach and scope of the program.
- Assisted with hosting and facilitating an official international event ceremony of students from Guam, televised on a Japanese news broadcast.

Native English Teacher (NET)

Hirakata City Board of Education Hirakata, Japan

04/2012 - 07/2015

- Established a pen pal letter exchange project which involved 16 junior high school classes with Japanese language classes in the US and included a LIVE video chat conference.
- Experienced with motion design and video creation to create green screen visual effects, special effects, and video animation effects.
- Incorporated Final Cut Pro X and Adobe After Effects for extensive video editing on students' public speaking presentations.
- Revitalized graph design illustrations of the second-year JHS school trip to Uji city, Kyoto.

Other Teaching Experience

Assistant English Teacher (AET) - City Staff/ Ivy/ Interac Co., LTD

Takatsuki City Board of Education 04/2009 – 01/2012

Kakogawa City Board of Education 09/2005 – 03/2006 & 04/2007 – 03/2009

Tech Industry Work Experience

Sales/Marketing

Pacific Software Publishing Bellevue, WA

09/2006 - 03/2007

- Met with clients to discuss the Pacific Software Publishing web & email hosting services.
- Documented preparation such as proposals, estimates, and contracts.

https://www.linkedin.com/in/annettelee2020